Contact

Vasantham 4/85 new number 33,redfields,puliakulam,appusamy naidu layout, Coimbatore-641045 9751881998 (Mobile) alvinorockc@karunya.edu.in

www.linkedin.com/in/alvinorock (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Deep Learning
Data Warehousing
SQL

Languages

Hindi

Tamil

English

Certifications

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2019 Certified Architect Professional

CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks

Prathamic examination

Desktop publishing (DTP)

Madhyama examination

Honors-Awards

Highest SGPA(9.44) in second semester at Karunya university

Centum in Science and Social sciences at 10th Std Government Examinations

100% Attendence in 1st,2nd and 3rd year at Karunya university

First Prize in English Elocution

First Prize in Tamil Elocution

Publications

A novelty technique for measuring human body paramaters using Big data analytics-IOT

Alvino rock

TCS Ninja -Application development and maintenance domain || Ex Intern at NUS || Ex Intern at HPE || IEEE & SCOPUS Author || 6X Oracle Certified || Network, Cloud & Datascience Aspirant Coimbatore

Summary

I am a TCS Ninja qualified candidate in Generic IT(Application development and maintainence) domain through TCSNQT-TCS National Qualifier Test(TCS NQT is a national level test conducted by tcs to hire candidates for specialized software profile) Enthusiastic techie guy who has passion in wide range of computer science areas like big data,machine learning,security,devops,blockchain technologies.Passionate to attend workshops,meetups,technical events,online courses to learn new technologies.

Experience

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences (Deemed university) 1 year 11 months

Academic Research Intern
December 2019 - May 2020 (6 months)
Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- * This Academic Research Internship titled "Skin lesion classification using machine learning" is my final year Btech CSE project carried under Dr.Bijolin Edwin, Assistant Professor, CSE, Karunya university
- * It was done on Apple ios platform using core ml,create ml,google firebase and is deployed in an app.

Academic Researcher
July 2018 - May 2020 (1 year 11 months)
Coimbatore Area, India

- * Working for paper presentation and publications in areas of rfid,big data,iot,bandwidth communication,artificial intelligence with Dr.Roopa Jeyasingh,Assistant professor,ECE,Karunya university and Wipro Limited buisness analyst JEBA KUMAR R J S .
- * Published paper in an Elsevier Scopus Indexed International journal IJRTE
- * Published Al journal in IGI Global book chapter

Interferenceless channel allocation using rfid for dynamic mesh network

Interference less channel allocation routing and energy minimization in wireless mesh network

Performance Analysis on Hybrid Wireless Mesh Network Topology Using Interference Aware Bandwidth Reservation

Augmented data prediction efficiency for Wireless Sensor Network application by Al-ML Technology (201219-030241)

- * Published conference paper in IEEE Xplore Digital Library
- * Presented paper presentations in ICSPC 2019 by IEEE and Karunya university,NCTERM 2018 by GM institute of technology,ICSTEM 2019 by Kalaignar karunanidhi institute of technology

NUS Computing
Winter Intern
December 2019 - January 2020 (2 months)
National university of Singapore, Singapore

*NUS is ranked 1st in Singapore & Asia Pacific, and 22nd in the world according to the 2018 Times Higher Education World University Rankings, and 11th in the world according to the 2019 QS World University Rankings. NUS was named the world's 4th most international university. In the QS Graduate Employability Rankings 2018, an annual ranking of university graduates' employability, NUS was ranked 30th in the world. In 2019, it ranked 27th among the universities around the world by SCImago Institutions Rankings.

*This project was winter internship program conducted at NUS School of Computing, National university of Singapore. This internship was a Global Academic Internship Program(GAIP) was organized by Corporate Gurukul.

*This internship was a full day training given by NUS professors and HPE worker on deep learning. Everyday we were conducted assessments.

*Finally we had to make a project on Garbage classification solution using Machine learning as a group with students from Srm, Bits Pilani, Psg.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise
Winter Intern
December 2019 - January 2020 (2 months)
National university of Singapore

DATA ANALYTICS USING DEEP LEARNING:

It is an academic program as a part of the Global Academic Internship Program by Corporate Gurukul. I worked on a deep learning project under my mentors Maheen Jaiswal and Shantanu Pandey!

IBM

Industrial elective - Semester Intern July 2019 - November 2019 (5 months) Karunya institute of technology and sciences

* Worked under IBM Cloud solution architect Mr.Rajesh Jeyapaul at Machine learning lab, Karunya university.

- * He initially trained us in learning machine learning courses from cognitive class.ai.
- * Later he made us to do projects from ibm code projects. Finally he made us member of 2 to design a project titled "Network intrusion detection system"
- * Organized IBM Meetup on " Artificial intelligence Neural architecture search " headed by IBM technical architect, Rajesh Jeyapaul It was a part of our industrial elective " Applied Machine learning lab". Students from across coimbatore from various branches like agriculture, electronics, computer science attended. Even startup owners attended the meeting.

Gogreen tech solution
Industrial Training - Winter intern
December 2018 - January 2019 (2 months)
Saravanampatti, Coimbatore

This industrial training was done on cctv camera devices operation and maintainence

MindMade Technologies
Summer Intern
May 2018 - June 2018 (2 months)
,Rathnam tech park,Coimbatore Area, India

- * Internship titled "Graphic designing and web development" was carried out on search engine optimization ,php backend validation , front end development .
- * Various machine learning and data analytics processes done in an industry were learnt during this internship. Tools used where like php, bootstrap code, html, css.

Education

National University of Singapore
Academic Internship Program, Data Analytics Using Deep
Learning · (2019 - 2020)

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences (Deemed university)
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science and
Engineering · (2016 - 2020)

Annamalai University

Diploma, Accupuncture · (2018 - 2019)

Carmel Garden Matriculation Higher Secondary School 12th Std Tamilnadu Matriculation board, Maths,Physics,Chemistry,Biology · (2014 - 2016)

Carmel Garden Matriculation Higher Secondary School

10th Std Tamilnadu Matriculation Board, English, Tamil, Maths, Science, Social science · (2002 - 2014)